<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM "rfc2629.dtd" [

<!-- One method to get references from the online citation libraries.
     There has to be one entity for each item to be referenced. 
     An alternate method (rfc include) is described in the references. -->
<!ENTITY RFC2119 SYSTEM "http://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2119.xml">
<!ENTITY RFC2629 SYSTEM "http://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2629.xml">
<!ENTITY RFC3552 SYSTEM "http://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.3552.xml">
<!ENTITY I-D.narten-iana-considerations-rfc2434bis SYSTEM "http://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml3/reference.I-D.narten-iana-considerations-rfc2434bis.xml">
]>

<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='rfc2629.xslt' ?>

<?rfc strict="yes" ?>
<?rfc toc="yes"?>
<?rfc tocdepth="4"?>
<?rfc symrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc sortrefs="yes" ?>
<?rfc compact="yes" ?>
<?rfc subcompact="no" ?>

<rfc category="info" docName="internet-draft" ipr="trust200902">
  <front>
    <title abbrev="">The Alpha Male Pack Protocol</title>

    <author fullname="Leland Andrew Olsen" initials="LAO" role="editor"
            surname="Olsen">
      <organization>OS3 LLC</organization>

      <address>
        <postal>
          <street></street>
          <city>Littleton</city>
          <region>USA West</region>
          <code>Colorado</code>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
        <phone>+1.801.360.4086</phone>
        <email>andy@59clouds.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>

    <date month="October" year="2015" />
    <area>General</area>
    <workgroup>Internet Engineering Task Force</workgroup>
    <keyword>Distributed</keyword>
    <keyword>Leadership</keyword>
    <keyword>Protocol</keyword>

    <abstract>
      <t>A protocol to allow many disparate actors to assemble
      spontaneously and form a leadership heirarchy.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>

  <middle>

    <section title="Introduction">
      <section title="Impetus">
        <t>This protocol exists as a way to allow any number of equal
        peers to come together and choose a leadership heierarchy.</t>
      </section>

      <section title="Prerequisites">
        <t>This protocol presumes the existence of Global Timestamp
        Protocol Server to allow the various peers to agree what time
        it is.</t>
        <t>This protocol also uses the Pseudo random identity
        protocol.</t>
      </section>

      <section title="Overview">
        <t>Given any number of nodes between 2 and infinity, already
        connected together via a communications channel, each node
        will perform the following actions:
        <list style="symbols">
          <t>Achieve Peer Group Consensus and agree to a definite time
          for the election with the Peer Global Time Consensus.</t>
          <t>At the agreed to time, broadcast the blockchain id from
          the Global TimeStamp Server and a personal peer random
          commit string to all the other peers in the group.</t>
          <t>Receive all other votes from all other peers.</t>
          <t>Walk the list of peers. For each peer, hash the timestamp
          block id and the random commit string from each peer. Now
          sort the list of peers based on this new hash value. Reject
          any peer who does not have a valid timestamp blockchain id
          or random commit string.</t>
          <t>Now walk the list of nodes and hash all the random
          commits strings in the new order. This is the election
          key.</t>
          <t>Finally, walk the list of peers one last time and hash
          the random commit string with the election key. Sort the
          list of peers by this final election hash and hash the list
          one last time.</t>
          <t>rebroadcast this final hash and all peers who come up
          with the same value have now all agreed to the order of
          succession to be king.</t>
          <t>Finally, apply some organizational model to the list of
          peers in the order everyone has agreed to to form a working
          government.</t>
        </list>
        </t>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section title="Peer Global Time Consensus">
      <t>Given a list of peers, each of whom is unknown to the other,
      a dance must be performed to identity all parties and to agree
      what time it is. Here are the steps for doing this:
        <list style="symbols">
          <t>Generate and broadcast a pseudo identity.</t>
          <t>Collect all other broadcast psuedo identities.</t>
          <t>Choose a Global TimeStamp 2 mins in the future and send
          the nomination to all other parties.</t>
          <t>Receive the other nomination from all other peers.</t>
          <t>Iterate through the list and choose the most popular
          TimeStamp from the list of nominations and rebroadcast this
          as a vote.</t>
          <t>Receive the rebroadcast votes of all the other peers.</t>
          <t>Keep all the peers who shared your vote and discard the
          rest. You now have your known list of peers and the time you
          have agreed to hold the election.</t>
        </list>
      </t>
    </section>

    <section title="government models">
      <section title="Monarchy">
        <t>The first peer on the list is the king.</t>
        <t>The next 10 are dukes.</t>
        <t>The next 10 go to the first duke as Earls. The next 10 to
        the 2nd Duke as Earls etc until all Duke's have 10 Earls.</t>
        <t>The next 10 go the first Earl as Viscounts following the
        same pattenrs until all Earls have 10 viscounts.</t>
        <t>The next 10 go to first viscount as Barons repeating the
        pattern until all Viscounts have 10 Barons.</t>
        <t>The next 10 go to the first Baron as Knight of the
        Realm. Repeast.</t>
        <t>The next 10 go to the first Knight as Serfs.</t>
      </section>

      <section title="Empire">
        <t>The first peer in the list is declared the Emporer.</t>
        <t>The next 64 peers in the list are assigned to the Senate,
        dedicated to supporting the Emporer.</t>
        <t>The remainder of the list of peers is divided into 64 list
        of peers. The first remaining peer goes in the first slot of
        list one and the second remaining peer goes in the first slot
        of group 2 etc until the list has been exhausted and the 64
        lists are as full as possible.</t>
        <t>Each list is then subdivided along the same lines as the
        Monarchy with the first peer in each list being King and
        swearing fealty to the corresponding Senator who then reports
        to the Emporer.</t>
      </section>

      <section title="Confederacy">
        <t>The list of peers is divided into 64 list of peers. The
        first peer goes in the first slot of list one and the second
        peer goes in the first slot of group 2 etc until the list has
        been exhausted and the 64 lists are as full as possible.</t>
        <t>Each of the 64 lists is then organized into a
        government.</t> <t>The first peer is President, the next 100
        are Senators, the next 1024 are house of commons, and the
        remainder of the list is even divided into 1024 lists.</t>
      </section>

      <section title="Quorum">
        <t>The list of peers is divided into an unknown number of
        quorums, each with 64 peers. Each of these Quorums is known as
        the Quorum of the People.</t>
        <t>The senior member of each Quorum of the People also joins a
        list called the Quorum of the County.</t>
        <t>The senior member of each Quorum of the County also joins a
        list called the Quorum of the State.</t>
        <t>The senior member of each Quorum of the State also joins a
        list called the Quorum of the Nation.</t>
        <t>The senior member of each Quorum of the Nation also joins a
        list called the Quorum of the Confederacy.</t>
      </section>

      <section title="Feminocracy">
        <t>The list of peers is divided into an equal number of groups
        of a single peer each. Each peer spend all his time arguing
        with every other peer about who has the best hair.</t>
      </section>

    </section>

    <?rfc needLines="8" ?>

    <section anchor="Acknowledgements" title="Acknowledgements">
      <t>This template was derived from an initial version written by Pekka
      Savola and contributed by him to the xml2rfc project.</t>

      <t>This document is part of a plan to make xml2rfc indispensable.</t>
    </section>

    <!-- Possibly a 'Contributors' section ... -->

    <section anchor="IANA" title="IANA Considerations">
      <t>This memo includes no request to IANA.</t>

      <t>All drafts are required to have an IANA considerations section (see
       for a guide). If the draft does not require IANA to do
      anything, the section contains an explicit statement that this is the
      case (as above). If there are no requirements for IANA, the section will
      be removed during conversion into an RFC by the RFC Editor.</t>
    </section>

    <section anchor="Security" title="Security Considerations">
      <t>All drafts are required to have a security considerations section.
      See for a guide.</t>
    </section>
  </middle>

  <!--  *****BACK MATTER ***** -->

  <back>
    <section anchor="app-additional" title="Additional Stuff">
      <t>This becomes an Appendix.</t>
    </section>
  </back>
</rfc>
